FAHAD NASRULLAH

H# 50, St# 5, Al-Faisal town, Lahore. Pakistan +923226601098 fahad.nasrullah109@gmail.com

I'm a Sr. SWE Android with over a decade of engineering and three years of leadership experience. All of my work has been in high-paced, low-resource environments (mostly startups) that demand technical excellence and efficient processes. The experience has led to a combination of technical and non-technical (business, project management) competence, which translates to effective decision making and valuable contributions to any team I'm a part of.

SKILLS

Android, Java, Kotlin, MVVM, MVI, Clean Architecture, CI/CD, Databases, Unit Testing, Hilt, Jetpack, RxKotlin, Kotlin Flows, Coroutines, Jetpack compose

WORK EXPERIENCE

Principal Software Engineer - Android

01/2023 to Present

Rayn - Remote

- Orchestrated the development of a native Android app using MAD techniques for Polio eradication, integrated real-time tracking and analytics features resulting in a 40% increase in vaccination coverage in high-risk areas.
- Enhanced GCSS Mobile app's crash-free rate from 81% to 99.9%
- Deployed Bitrise workflows for 2 mobile applications, significantly enhancing build efficiency and reducing deployment time by 50%, resulting in a 20% increase in app performance and stability.
- Achieved 55% test coverage for GCSS mobile app, ensuring reliability.
- Provided the team with comprehensive unit testing training, resulting in increasing test coverage of projects.
- Authored industry-focused blogs for Rayn's website.
- Developed POC mobile apps in Flutter and KMM.
- Technologies: Android App development, MVVM, Bitrise, Firebase, Room, Coroutines, Clean architecture, Flutter, KMP

Sr. SWE (L5) - Android

03/2022 to 12/2022

SWVL - Remote

- Worked on Backup Shift feature for Captain App which increase captain visibility for rides by 90% and reduced Robo calls for captain
- Worked on QR Check-in feature for Captain App which help B2B captains to onboard multiple users on a single station using QR scanning
- Integrated Dexguard on Captain app to restrict app from reverse engineering and for better code obfuscation
- Increase Test coverage from 5 to 25 % by constantly writing unit tests
- Improved Captain app's crash free users from 78 to 97%
- Improved whole captain app's UI to new designs
- Technologies: RxJava, MVI, Bitrise, Firebase, Room, Coroutines, Clean architecture

Principal Software Engineer - Android

01/2021 to 03/2022

Confiz Limited - Lahore, Pakistan

- Developed two apps from start to end for Android in Fintech domain, using Multi-modular approach on MVVM architecture
- Added Firebase Analytics for the whole app to track user journey and created funnels to view the number of users going through a certain path, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement.
- Introduced CI/CD in an android project using Bitrise and created workflows to generate builds for UAT/QA, resulting in a 50% decrease in deployment time.
- Added test cases for presentation layer and improved test coverage of project upto 40%
- Technologies: MVVM, Kotlin Bitrise, Firebase, Coroutines, Clean architecture

Principal Software Engineer - Android

04/2017 to 03/2020

Cincorios Pvt Ltd - Lahore, Pakistan

- Managed team of 5 engineers by assigning sprint tasks and helping technically in achieving their targets
- Developed VOD solutions for Tablets and TV's installed on 150+ busses having 30 or 50 seats
- Integrated Countly, as hosted solution within bus's server for analytics that can work offline
- Integrated Revive Ad server to keep track of Pre/Mid/Post roll ads played on Tablets/TV/Phones
- Developed Mobile apps for different clients which passengers can use on their cell-phones inside bus to enjoy content without internet connectivity
- Compiled AOSP to create custom android ROM for tablets having Restart permission enabled and VOD app as default launcher
- Technologies: Android, Java, Kotlin, MVP

Senior Software Engineer

03/2016 to 04/2017

Netsol Technologies - Lahore, Pakistan

- Worked on creating Sample Apps for WRLD 3D maps having core written in C++ using NDK
- Worked on creating Sample Apps for WRLD 3D maps with their AR/VR and Unity 3D plugin
- Contributed WRLD3D's platform features written in C++
- Technologies: Android, NDK, C++, Java, C#, NDK, Unit3d

Senior Software Engineer

12/2014 to 03/2016

Ciklum - Lahore

- · Worked dedicated with client from Denmark and developed health application named Spiromagic
- Communication with client for taking requirements or giving demos
- Technologies: Android, Java, BLE, MVC

Android Developer

07/2011 to 12/2014

Coeus Solutions GmbH - Lahore, Pakistan

- I worked as a dedicated resource for Prinovis Ltd. & Co. KG at Coeus-Solutions GmbH, to develop and maintain their Android projects
- Technologies: Android, Java, MVC

EDUCATION

National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences

Bachelor's Computer Science

08/2007 to 07/2011

AWARDS

Gold Medalist

07/2011

I am Gold Medalist of my batch at FAST in BSCS and I have secured 3.83 gpa out of 4.

First Prize in CS Quiz Competition at NUTEC

04/2010

My team won the first prize in the CS Quiz Competition in NUTEC held at FAST Peshawar in 2010.

First Prize in Software Project Competition at NUTEC

03/201

We won the first prize in the Software Project Competition at NUTEC held at FAST Peshawar in 2011. Our FYP was on Android named **Mobile based Travel Assistant**.

ICT R&D Scholarship

06/2007

I got an ICT R&D Scholarship for BSCS at FAST University.

LINKS

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/fahadnasrullah

Github: https://github.com/fahadnasrullah109

HackerRank: https://www.hackerrank.com/fahad_nasrullah1